# Moiz-Ur-Rehman Azmat

Nationality: Pakistani Date of birth: 16/06/1999 Phone number: (+92) 3435995776

Email address: moizurrehman0341@gmail.com in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/moeezrehman/

**Website:** <a href="https://moiz-ur-rehman.github.io/portfolio/">https://moiz-ur-rehman.github.io/portfolio/</a>

• Home: Islamabad (Pakistan)

### **ABOUT ME**

Experienced web developer with a strong background in developing award-winning applications for a diverse clientele. 3 years of industry experience includes programming, debugging, and designing. Skilled in NodeJS, React JS, MongoDB, and SQL. Team player with an eye for detail. Passionate in working, highly motivated & goal oriented with a sincere commitment to excellence.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Full Stack Engineer**

ISMMART Group of Industries [ 25/10/2022 - Current ]

**City:** Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- Designed, developed, and maintained web-based applications using NodeJS, ReactJS, NextJS, MYSQL, MongoDb and AWS
- Led successful launch of several key projects including an e-commerce platform i.e ismmart.com
- Designing and managing database, including writing database queries and performing database optimizations
- Analyzing project requirements and devising effective plans and solutions for their successful implementation
- Built and maintained RESTful APIs and integrated them with front-end components

### **Backend Developer**

**QuellxCode Pvt Ltd** [ 19/01/2022 - 10/11/2022 ]

**City:** Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- Worked on an existing enterprise project
- Developing Rest APIs for mobile ,web and game applications
- Technologies: NodeJS, MongoDB, ReactJS, Firebase, Stripe, Redis
- Deployments on AWS and bug fixing

## **Full Stack Engineer**

**Tech Flickers** [ 10/08/2021 - 24/09/2021 ]

City: Remote

- Design and development of web applications
- Development using technologies like React JS, Node JS, Mongo Db, ExpressJS, Firebase Integration

### **Full Stack Developer**

**Innovativity** [ 16/08/2021 – 24/09/2021 ]

City: Remote

- Making updates to existing web-based applications
- Development using technologies like React.IS, Dot-Net, and MySQL

# **Frontend Developer**

*Fiverr* [ 07/08/2021 - 26/09/2022 ]

**City:** Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- Completed many frontend projects on different freelancing websites for client around the globe
- Worked on admin panels and landing pages with animations
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, React JS, GSAP Animation

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science**

Capital University of Science and Technology [ 10/09/2018 – 30/07/2022 ]

Address: Islamabad (Pakistan) Website: https://cust.edu.pk/

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

JavaScript / Node.js / React.js / MySQL / MongoDB / Express / TypeScript / Git/GitHub / Firebase / Docker / CSS / HTML / Python / Redis / Payment Systems / Next JS / AWS EC2 / AWS S3 / AWS RDS / Data Structures / Algorithms

# **PROJECTS**

#### **Personal Portfolio Website**

[ 01/05/2021 - 01/06/2021 ]

Developed using HTML,CSS and JavaScript

Link: https://moiz-ur-rehman.github.io/portfolio

# Job Portal with CV Ranking and Online Test

[ 15/09/2021 - 17/07/2022 ]

- Final Year Project
- Technologies: Python, Node JS, React JS, MySQL, AWS(EC2+RDS)

#### **Brain Tumor Detection**

[ 01/04/2022 - 01/05/2022 ]

• Designed a Deep Learning model which can detect if a person have brain tumor or not using MRI Images

### **CERTIFICATES**

## **Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp (Samsung Innovation Campus)**

[ 01/02/2022 - 01/05/2022 ]

#### Frontend Fundamentals (pirple)

[ 06/01/2020 - 06/02/2020 ]

### Data Science methodology (IBM)

[ 20/02/2021 - 20/03/2021 ]

## **Data Analysis with python (IBM)**

[ 01/04/2021 - 01/05/2021 ]

# Tools for Data science (IBM)

[18/01/2021 - 18/02/2021]